intel.com 2008-06-26

# Intel® Privacy Policy

_To read the Intel® Privacy Policy in another language, choose from the options in the menu to the left._

Intel is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring you have a positive experience on our website. This policy outlines our personal information handling practices for both online and offline data. If you give us personal information, we will treat it according to this policy.

We encourage you to read this privacy policy to ensure you understand Intel's privacy practices.

Intel Corporation is proudly affiliated with the [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.intel.com&sealid=101) and [BBBOnLine](http://www.bbb.org/) privacy seal organizations.

If you are not satisfied with our response to your privacy-related concerns, please contact [BBBOnLine](http://www.bbb.org/) or [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php).

This policy covers the Intel Corporate website and is applicable worldwide. Some of our subsidiaries or programs may have their own, possibly different, policies (see lists at right). We encourage you to read this privacy policy and those of all websites you visit.

back to top

## Collection of your personal information

When Intel collects any personal information on our corporate website, we will express our need for the personal data at the point of collection. Personal information is any information that can be used to identify an individual, and may include, but is not limited to, name, email address, postal or other physical address, title, occupation, and other information required to provide a service, deliver a product, or carry out a transaction you have requested. Some of the reasons we collect your personal information include:

  * participation in discussion groups
  * collaboration efforts
  * registration to membership programs or newsletter subscriptions
  * provide registered users a more personalized and meaningful experience on the Intel website.

back to top

## Uses of your personal information

We will only use your personal information in the way we specified when it was collected. We will not subsequently change the way your personal information is used without your consent. Some of the ways we may use your personal information include:

  * To provide the ability to create personal profile areas and view protected content.
  * To provide the ability to contact you, and provide you with shipping and billing information.
  * To provide customer feedback and support.
  * To provide contests, sweepstakes or other marketing or promotional activities on the intel.com or affiliate websites. Personal information may be collected to administer those programs.
  * To conduct questionnaires and surveys in order to provide better products and services to our customers and end users. Your completion of any questionnaires is voluntary.
  * To support recruitment inquiries. For more information, please see the worldwide Candidate Privacy Policy.
  * To understand more about you, so we can personalize newsletters and websites to your preferences. For example, allow you the opportunity to request specific information on products and services that may be of interest.
  * To allow you to forward information to another individual such as a friend or co-worker. Intel does not store the personal information of the third party. We collect the information for the sole purpose of sending a one-time email. If you choose to use our referral service to inform a colleague or friend, we will only ask for a contact name and email address.
  * To meet contract obligations.

back to top

## Accessing and updating your personal information

We need your help in keeping the personal information you have shared with us accurate and up to date. Please notify us of any changes to your personal information.

Most of our sites allow you to make these updates yourself online via a particular program's member pages or the [Intel Profile Center](https://ssl.intel.com/ipc-app/default.aspx)

back to top

## Unsubscribing

Subscriptions to some newsletters can be managed through the Intel Online Subscriptions website. In addition, each email newsletter includes instructions on how you can unsubscribe from that particular mailing.

You may also unsubscribe from Intel's various newsletters by sending a letter, including your name, email address and the title of the marketing material you wish to unsubscribe from to:

Intel Corporation  
Unsubscribe/Privacy  
M/S RNB4-145  
2200 Mission College Blvd  
Santa Clara, CA 95054  

back to top

## Non-personal information collection

In some instances, Intel may collect non-personal (aggregate or demographic) data through cookies, web logs, and web beacons. This information is used to better understand and improve the usability, performance, and effectiveness of the Intel.com website.

back to top

## Sharing your personal information

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third-parties for marketing purposes unless you have granted us permission to do so.

We may share your personal information within Intel or any of our worldwide subsidiaries for purposes of data processing or storage.

We may also share your personal information with authorized third-party agents or contractors in order to provide a requested service or transaction. For example, if we need to ship something to you, we must share your name and address with a shipping company. We only provide third-party agents with the minimum amount of personal information necessary to complete the requested service or transaction.

We may respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process by disclosing your personal information and other related information, if necessary. We also may choose to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

We may collect and possibly share personal information and any other additional information available to us in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Intel's terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

While navigating Intel's web site you may be directed to content or functionality that is hosted by a third party supplier, not on Intel.com. This is typically done to host special events, such as contests. When information is collected on behalf of Intel exclusively, Intel's privacy policy will be referenced on the site and will govern how your information is used. For other, non-Intel sites, the site owner's privacy policy will be referenced. It is Intel's practice to require such suppliers to handle information in a manner consistent with Intel's privacy and security policies.

We will ask you for your opt-in consent to share your personal information with a third party for any other reason.

back to top

## Personalization

We may customize websites or newsletters for certain users based on the information they previously provided or that was collected through Intel.com websites in order to enhance the overall web experience.

back to top

## Security of your personal information

Intel is committed to protecting the personal information you share with us. We utilize a combination of security technologies, procedures, and organizational measures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

When we transfer sensitive personal data (for example, credit card information) over the Internet, we protect it using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology.

While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit.

We recommend you to take every precaution in protecting your personal information when you are on the Internet. For example, change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers when creating passwords, and make sure you use a secure browser.

back to top

## Cookies

Intel websites utilize cookies, although you can still access most of them even if you choose to disable cookies in your browser. Some websites will not allow you to complete certain activities if cookies are disabled. For example, our consumer e-commerce site (i.e. ShopIntelSM) uses session cookies and persistent cookies to process transactions. If you do not accept cookies, the associated shopping basket will not work and you will not be able to place an order.

We use multiple third parties to monitor web traffic, statistics, advertisement 'click-through', and other activities on Intel's sites. Where authorized by Intel, such third parties may use cookies, Intel's web log files, web beacons, and other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous aggregate statistics on Intel's website visitors.

We also include web beacons in HTML-formatted e-mail newsletters in order to count how many newsletters (or particular articles, links, etc.) are being accessed.

Current versions of web browsers offer enhanced user controls regarding the placement and duration of both first and third party cookies. Search for "cookies" under your web browser's Help menu for more information on cookie management features available to you.

back to top

## Data retention

Intel will not retain your personal information longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations.

back to top

## Linked websites

Our websites may provide links to other third-party websites which are outside our control and not covered by this policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these (and all) sites.

back to top

## Newsgroups/forums

Intel newsgroups and forums are public. Please consider this before posting material to them.

back to top

## Children's privacy

Intel does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that data from our systems. Intel encourages parents and guardians to go online with their children. Here are a few tips to help make a child's online experience safer:

  * Teach children never to give personal information (such as name, address, phone number, school, etc.) unless supervised by a parent or responsible adult.
  * Know the sites your children are visiting and which sites are appropriate.
  * Look for website privacy policies. Know how your child's information is treated.

Please visit the [FTC's website](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/kidzprivacy/index.html) for more tips on protecting children's privacy online.

back to top

## Transfer of personal information

We may transfer your personal information to Intel Corporation in the US, to any Intel subsidiary worldwide, or to third parties acting on our behalf for the purposes of processing or storage.

back to top

## Validating of our privacy practices

In order to further demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to have our privacy practices reviewed for compliance by both [BBBOnLine](http://www.bbb.org/) and [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/).

  * Intel is a proud holder of the BBBOnLine privacy seal which applies to our English language websites.
  * Intel is also proud holder of the TRUSTe privacy seal (which applies to online, English language websites at this time. By participating in the TRUSTe privacy program, Intel agrees in the importance of notifying you of the following:
  * What information of yours is collected.
  * How your information is used.
  * With whom we may share your information.

**Note** : The TRUSTe program covers information that is collected through this website and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the site.

back to top

## Need assistance?

Need help with an update, access, or unsubscribe request? Please contact us by using this form. To aid in processing your request, please include the following details:

  * Your contact information
  * Name of the program where you want the update applied
  * Details of the request (e.g. change of e-mail address, unsubscribe from a newsletter, review of personal information, etc.)

back to top

## Supplement for Intel® Core™2 processor with Viiv™ technology

We have a supplement which describes our privacy-related information handling practices for the Windows* Media* Digital Rights Management (WM-DRM) Software Premium Content Module (SPCM) for Intel Core 2 processor with Viiv technology. We encourage you to review the information contained in this supplement to ensure you understand how the SPCM operates to help you enjoy specific types of premium content with your Intel Core 2 processor with Viiv technology-based home network.

back to top

## Questions or comments?

Please review the privacy policy frequently asked questions (FAQs) for more details. Should you have any additional privacy-related questions or comments related to this privacy policy, please use this form to contact us.

back to top

## Policy updates

The Intel Privacy Policy has been recently updated. For more details on the changes to the policy, please visit our FAQs.

Last update: **April 21, 2006**
